<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Blog on Harald W. Bøe</title><link>https://hboe.no/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Harald W. Bøe</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.152.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:53:19 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hboe.no/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Omarchy</title><link>https://hboe.no/blog/omarchy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hboe.no/blog/omarchy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a new Linux distribution in town, and it&amp;rsquo;s making waves.
&lt;a href="https://omarchy.org/"&gt;Omarchy&lt;/a&gt; is an arch-linux based distribution intended for developers and its quickly gaining popularity since it&amp;rsquo;s release this summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creator is David Heinemeier Hansson (DHH). DHH is the creator of Ruby on Rails and CTO of &lt;a href="https://37signals.com/"&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt;. From what I&amp;rsquo;ve understood the reason for creating it is that he was fed up by the decline of macs and started looking into how Linux fared as a developer OS.
Well, he did indeed put together something quite awesome for developers. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few highlights that comes to mind:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tools I use</title><link>https://hboe.no/blog/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hboe.no/blog/tools/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently got a new work computer and went through the process of setting it up.
In the likely event that I need to go trough this process again I&amp;rsquo;ve listed most of the tools and documented the installation process of them.&lt;br&gt;
The list is non-exhaustive as I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten some kind of obscure linux CLI tool I use once a month.
Whenever I discover something new or swap out a tool I&amp;rsquo;ll document it here.&lt;br&gt;
My development workflow revolves heavily around WSL so the biggest section is related to getting a nice Linux development environment inside WSL setup.
Hopefully you&amp;rsquo;ll find something cool in here.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a personal website with Hugo and Github Pages</title><link>https://hboe.no/blog/personal_website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hboe.no/blog/personal_website/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of different frameworks, tools and platforms available when building a personal website today.&lt;br&gt;
In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll go into how and why I chose to build my webpage using the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/"&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; framework. I&amp;rsquo;ll also show how to setup the hosting on Github pages which includes pushing the webpage from a private repository to a public one with Github Actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My requirements for the tech stack were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to create and manage content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content version control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automated deployment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo is a static site generator which typically makes loading of webpages extremely fast.
Static sites are also in general low maintenance.
All content are markdown files which makes it easy to see changes with git and makes the content highly portable.
By hosting it on github pages we get automated deployment from github actions and low cost. I only pay for the domain itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>